Kuiyao Qiao

Professional Profile

Emerging Data Analyst. Insightful. Studies discovery as well as design. Expert at discovering patterns in complex datasets and using different tools and methods to demonstrate the meaning of data. Passionate about explaining complex raw data visually to the masses.

Education

Bachelor of Information

2024

Faculty of Information, University of Toronto

(expected)

Representative Courses: Interface design fundamentals, Computational Reasoning, hardware design and software interaction. Information Practices in Organizations Object-Based

Bachelor of Arts 2022-2023

Information Technology, York University

Object-Based Programming, Data Structures, Systems Analysis and Design, Using and Designing Database Systems, Designing User Interfaces

Arts and Science 2019-2021

Art and Science Program, Seneca College

Relevant : Functions and Relations, Academic Research and Writing, Calculus, and Critical Thinking

Projects

Problem identification, survey, and prototype system production

2024

- Identify user groups, discover and investigate specific user needs and pain points.
- Prepare data, analyse, interpret and conceptualise the problems identified.
- · Evaluate the design through usability and validity, from low-fidelity models to final high-fidelity models.

Cost Effective Offer Model

2023

- Collected and analyzed the data on used Volkswagen Tiguan vehicles (price, mileage, year, mechanical certification, etc.)
- Used Excel to build residuals table, residual plot, line fit plot, and the trend line
- Identified cost-effective offer scenarios based on the data

Database Project

2022

- Developed a database for an expanding bookstore to accommodate its accounting, inventory management, and storage needs
- Created an entity relationship model and used Microsoft Access to build a database

180 ENTERPRISE BLVD, MARKHAM ON L6G 1B3 | 437-983-7722 | KUIYAO.QIAO@MAIL.UTORONTO.CA

- Identified errors in the model and made necessary modifications
- Built logical and relational models for the database
- Used Access for the ISA relationship and the Many-to-Many data model
- Implemented features for user management, backend inventory control, and accounting

Professional Experience

Medical Data Analyst

2023-2024

Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital

- Uses different systems to generalise and summarise data
- Produces systems to distil data and performs final calculations on categories and consumables
- Categorise final data and optimise UI design

Laboratory Assistant

2015 - 2017

Nanjing University Biology Lab

- Cleaned and set up laboratory equipment
- Carried out experiments, recorded the results, and identified patterns in the data
- Translated research reports from Mandarin Chinese to English and reviewed publication drafts

Additional Experience

System Maintenance

2023-2024

• Maintenance of LifeWorks (TELUS Health) confidential consultations, counselling part of the old system to eliminate unexpected problems

Snowboard Instructor

(Toronto, Canada)

2019-2024

• Offered lessons for individuals and groups at the Blue Mountain Resort and Mount St. Louis

• Developed a solid client referral network by providing an exceptional client experience

Skills and Qualifications

- Python, Java, R, HTML, CSS, SQL, MATLAB
- Demonstrated data analysis skills
- Solid quantitative and qualitative research abilities
- Extensive background in mathematics and statistical science
- Microsoft Office Specialist (MOS) certificate
- Developed solid customer service and teamwork skills through multiple client-facing roles
- Languages: fluent in English and Mandarin Chinese
- CASI Level 2 snowboard Instructor